<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' standalone='no'?>
<doxygen xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="compound.xsd" version="1.9.6" xml:lang="en-US">
  <compounddef id="References" kind="page">
    <compoundname>References</compoundname>
    <title>References</title>
    <tableofcontents>
      <tocsect>
        <name>Conference</name>
        <reference>References_1RefConference</reference>
    </tocsect>
      <tocsect>
        <name>Journal</name>
        <reference>References_1RefJournal</reference>
    </tocsect>
      <tocsect>
        <name>Recognition</name>
        <reference>References_1RefRecognition</reference>
    </tocsect>
    </tableofcontents>
    <briefdescription>
    </briefdescription>
    <detaileddescription>
<para>This page summarizes a list of publication related to Taskflow. If you are using Taskflow, please cite the following paper we publised at 2022 IEEE TPDS:</para>
<para><itemizedlist>
<listitem><para>Tsung-Wei Huang, Dian-Lun Lin, Chun-Xun Lin, and Yibo Lin, "<ulink url="https://tsung-wei-huang.github.io/papers/tpds21-taskflow.pdf">Taskflow: A Lightweight Parallel and Heterogeneous Task Graph Computing System</ulink>," <emphasis>IEEE Transactions on Parallel and Distributed Systems (TPDS)</emphasis>, vol. 33, no. 6, pp. 1303-1320, June 2022</para>
</listitem></itemizedlist>
</para>
<sect1 id="References_1RefConference">
<title>Conference</title>
<para><orderedlist>
<listitem>
<para>Dian-Lun Lin, Yanqing Zhang, Haoxing Ren, Shih-Hsin Wang, Brucek Khailany and Tsung-Wei Huang, "<ulink url="https://tsung-wei-huang.github.io/papers/2023-dac.pdf">GenFuzz: GPU-accelerated Hardware Fuzzing using Genetic Algorithm with Multiple Inputs</ulink>," <emphasis>ACM/IEEE Design Automation Conference (DAC)</emphasis>, San Francisco, CA, 2023 </para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para>Tsung-Wei Huang, "<ulink url="https://tsung-wei-huang.github.io/papers/ipdps23.pdf">qTask: Task-parallel Quantum Circuit Simulation with Incrementality</ulink>," <emphasis>IEEE International Parallel and Distributed Processing Symposium (IPDPS)</emphasis>, St. Petersburg, Florida, 2023 </para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para>Elmir Dzaka, Dian-Lun Lin, and Tsung-Wei Huang, "<ulink url="https://tsung-wei-huang.github.io/papers/pdco-23.pdf">Parallel And-Inverter Graph Simulation Using a Task-graph Computing System</ulink>," <emphasis>IEEE International Parallel and Distributed Processing Symposium Workshop (IPDPSW)</emphasis>, St. Petersburg, Florida, 2023 </para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para>Tsung-Wei Huang and Leslie Hwang, "<ulink url="https://tsung-wei-huang.github.io/papers/hpec22-semaphore.pdf">Task-Parallel Programming with Constrained Parallelism</ulink>," <emphasis>IEEE High-Performance Extreme Computing Conference (HPEC)</emphasis>, MA, 2022 </para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para>Tsung-Wei Huang, "<ulink url="https://tsung-wei-huang.github.io/papers/hpec22-ot.pdf">Enhancing the Performance Portability of Heterogeneous Circuit Analysis Programs</ulink>," <emphasis>IEEE High-Performance Extreme Computing Conference (HPEC)</emphasis>, MA, 2022 </para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para>Dian-Lun Lin, Haoxing Ren, Yanqing Zhang, and Tsung-Wei Huang, "<ulink url="https://tsung-wei-huang.github.io/papers/icpp22-rtlflow.pdf">From RTL to CUDA: A GPU Acceleration Flow for RTL Simulation with Batch Stimulus</ulink>," <emphasis>ACM International Conference on Parallel Processing (ICPP)</emphasis>, Bordeaux, France, 2022 </para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para>Cheng-Hsiang Chiu and Tsung-Wei Huang, "<ulink url="https://doi.org/10.1145/3502181.3533714">Composing Pipeline Parallelism using Control Taskflow Graph</ulink>," <emphasis>ACM International Symposium on High-Performance Parallel and Distributed Computing (HPDC)</emphasis>, Minneapolis, Minnesota, 2022 </para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para>Cheng-Hsiang Chiu and Tsung-Wei Huang, "<ulink url="https://tsung-wei-huang.github.io/papers/dac2022.pdf">Efficient Timing Propagation with Simultaneous Structural and Pipeline Parallelisms</ulink>," <emphasis>ACM/IEEE Design Automation Conference (DAC)</emphasis>, San Francisco, CA, 2022 </para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para>Dian-Lun Lin and Tsung-Wei Huang, "Efficient GPU Computation using Task Graph Parallelism," <emphasis>European Conference on Parallel and Distributed Computing (EuroPar)</emphasis>, 2021 </para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para>Tsung-Wei Huang, "<ulink url="iccad20.pdf">A General-purpose Parallel and Heterogeneous Task Programming System for VLSI CAD</ulink>," <emphasis>IEEE/ACM International Conference on Computer-aided Design (ICCAD)</emphasis>, CA, 2020 </para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para>Chun-Xun Lin, Tsung-Wei Huang, and Martin Wong, "<ulink url="icpads20.pdf">An Efficient Work-Stealing Scheduler for Task Dependency Graph</ulink>," <emphasis>IEEE International Conference on Parallel and Distributed Systems (ICPADS)</emphasis>, Hong Kong, 2020 </para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para>Tsung-Wei Huang, Chun-Xun Lin, Guannan Guo, and Martin Wong, "<ulink url="ipdps19.pdf">Cpp-Taskflow: Fast Task-based Parallel Programming using Modern C++</ulink>," <emphasis>IEEE International Parallel and Distributed Processing Symposium (IPDPS)</emphasis>, pp. 974-983, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil, 2019 </para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para>Chun-Xun Lin, Tsung-Wei Huang, Guannan Guo, and Martin Wong, "<ulink url="mm19.pdf">A Modern C++ Parallel Task Programming Library</ulink>," <emphasis>ACM Multimedia Conference (MM)</emphasis>, pp. 2284-2287, Nice, France, 2019 </para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para>Chun-Xun Lin, Tsung-Wei Huang, Guannan Guo, and Martin Wong, "<ulink url="hpec19.pdf">An Efficient and Composable Parallel Task Programming Library</ulink>," <emphasis>IEEE High-performance and Extreme Computing Conference (HPEC)</emphasis>, pp. 1-7, Waltham, MA, 2019 </para>
</listitem>
</orderedlist>
</para>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="References_1RefJournal">
<title>Journal</title>
<para><orderedlist>
<listitem>
<para>Dian-Lun Lin and Tsung-Wei Huang, "<ulink url="https://tsung-wei-huang.github.io/papers/tpds22-snig.pdf">Accelerating Large Sparse Neural Network Inference using GPU Task Graph Parallelism</ulink>," <emphasis>IEEE Transactions on Parallel and Distributed Systems (TPDS)</emphasis>, vol. 33, no. 11, pp. 3041-3052, Nov 2022 </para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para>Tsung-Wei Huang, Dian-Lun Lin, Chun-Xun Lin, and Yibo Lin, "<ulink url="https://tsung-wei-huang.github.io/papers/tpds21-taskflow.pdf">Taskflow: A Lightweight Parallel and Heterogeneous Task Graph Computing System</ulink>," <emphasis>IEEE Transactions on Parallel and Distributed Systems (TPDS)</emphasis>, vol. 33, no. 6, pp. 1303-1320, June 2022 </para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para>Tsung-Wei Huang, Dian-Lun Lin, Yibo Lin, and Chun-Xun Lin, "<ulink url="tcad21-taskflow.pdf">Cpp-Taskflow: A General-purpose Parallel Task Programming System at Scale</ulink>," <emphasis>IEEE Transactions on Computer-aided Design of Integrated Circuits and Systems (TCAD)</emphasis>, vol. 40, no.8, 2021 </para>
</listitem>
</orderedlist>
</para>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="References_1RefRecognition">
<title>Recognition</title>
<para><orderedlist>
<listitem>
<para>Champion of Graph Challenge at the 2020 IEEE High-performance Extreme Computing Conference </para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para>Second Prize of Open-Source Software Competition at the 2019 ACM Multimedia Conference </para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para>ACM SIGDA Outstanding PhD Dissertation Award at the 2019 ACM/IEEE Design Automation Conference </para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para>Best Poster Award at the 2018 Official C++ Conference, voted by hundreds of C++ professionals </para>
</listitem>
</orderedlist>
</para>
</sect1>
    </detaileddescription>
    <location file="references/references.dox"/>
  </compounddef>
</doxygen>
